A Guide to the Papers of the Fontaine-Maury Society, 1910-1990
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the Fontaine-Maury Society 1910-1990
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6269-j
This collection consists of ca. 900 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were loaned to the Library by Charles E. Moran, Jr., of Free Union, Virginia, on September 21, 1990.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of 3 Hollinger boxes, ca. one linear foot), 1910-1990 (the majority of the material earlier than 1971 consists of newsclippings), the archives of the Fontaine/Maury Society, an association of the descendants and their families of Jacques Fontaine (1658-1728) and his wife Anne Elisabeth Boursiquot (d. 1721). Included is correspondence, minutes, research materials and notes, a scrapbook concerning a trip by a member of the Society to La Rocelle, France, in 1987, newsletters, miscellaneous printed items, and memorabilia.
Contents List
- Bagley, Beverly Maury 1989 (Box 1)
- Beaverdam Graveyard, Hanover County 1971-1981, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 1)
- Busfield, Kathleen N. 1987-1990 (Box 1)
- Catterall, Louise (FMC) to Chic Moran 1973-1975, 1980 (Box 1)
- Catterall, Louise F.: Notes & Correspondence re Fontaine and Meade Families 1937, 1971-1983, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 1)
- Clark, Genevieve 1989 (Box 1)
- Collins, Michael, Juanita, and Shirley Denhard 1988-1989 (Box 1)
- Covan, Elizabeth W. 1989 (Box 1)
- Currie, Randolph N. 1988-1989 (Box 1)
- Denhard, Shirley Juanita Collins 1990 (Box 1)
- Evans, Dorothy Taylor 1987 (Box 1)
- Falkoff, Fontaine 1989 (Box 1)
- Fontaine Family: Allied Families of Randolph, Dabney, Morris, Minor and Price 1931, 1946, 1977 (Box 1)
- Fontaine, Jacques (Rev. James) Memoirs of a Huguenot Family1987 (Box 1)
- Fontaine, John E. 1988 (Box 1)
- Fontaine, Joseph Boynton 1981-1990 (Box 1)
- Fontaine, Louise Neimyer 1913, 1962 (Box 2)
- Fontaine, Roger A. 1989-1990 (Box 2)
- Fontaine, William and Edmund 1973, n.d. (Box 2)
- Fontaine, Winston F. 1986-1990 (Box 2)
- Fontaine Society Meeting 1983-1990, (5 folders) (Box 2)
- Harris, F.R. 1989 (Box 2)
- Harrison, Alice Elizabeth Fontaine and Robert 1988 (Box 2)
- Heap, Roland G. 1988 (Box 2)
- Heath, Katherine Fontaine Syer 1975-1987 (Box 2)
- Hicks, Sallie Anne Werth (Mrs. Robert A.) 1988-1989 (Box 2)
- Hull, Warren R. 1987-1988 (Box 2)
- Jones, Catesby 1974, 1984 (Box 2)
- Jones, Rosalie Fontaine n.d. (Box 2)
- Jones, Viola H. 1989 (Box 2)
- Jontz, Billie (Mrs. William M.) 1988 (Box 2)
- Le Stourgeon, Lawrence Fontaine 1985-1990 (Box 2)
- Luckett, Helen H. 1989
- Mc Alexander, Hubert M. 1987-1989 (Box 3)
- Mann, William Berkeley 1975-1989 (Box 3)
- Membership Applications 1989-1990 (Box 3)
- Morris, William Maury 1988 (Box 3)
- Newsletters 1988-1991, (2 folders) (Box 3)
- Obituaries of Fontaine Family Members 1933-1982 (Box 3)
- Osborne, Matthew Fontaine Maury 1986-1990 (Box 3)
- Pipes, Elizabeth Barbour (Mrs. R. Ford) 1989 (Box 3)
- Ragland, Charles J. 1987 (Box 3)
- Ressinger, Diane "Dee Dee" (Mrs. John) 1988-1989 (Box 3)
- Riely, Jean Roy Jones 1974, 1984 (Box 3)
- Rose, Murray Fontaine 1989-1990 (Box 3)
- Safford, Barbara (Mrs. Charles D.) 1988-1990 (Box 3)
- Sanger, Roy Burdette 1986-1989 (Box 3)
- Soper, Mary Waller Shepherd 1989 (Box 3)
- Teague, Sue West 1988-1989 (Box 3)
- Turner, Barbara Fontaine 1988-1989 (Box 3)
- Valentine, Lila Meade: Newsclippings re the Suffrage of Women ca. 1910-1930 (Box 3)
- Honor Roll Certificate for Lila Meade Valentine National American Women Suffrage Association 1920 (Box 3)
- Waddell, Ronald L. 1988-1989 (Box 3)
- Whyte, Robert Page Morris 1989 (Box 3)
- Wolfe, Cynthia Nash 1989 (Box 3)
- Scrapbook re a Trip to La Rochelle, France, kept by Diane Ressinger 1987 (Box 3)
- Notes on Meade Family Letters and Other Family Records n.d. (Box 3)